<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computers on Purusothaman Ramanujam</title>
    <link>http://purusothaman.me/categories/computers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computers on Purusothaman Ramanujam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 23:57:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://purusothaman.me/categories/computers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Cron in Windows </title>
      <link>http://purusothaman.me/running-cron-in-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 23:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://purusothaman.me/running-cron-in-windows/</guid>
      <description>We all would have heard of Cron jobs, if you are involved in website management, development or working on Linux/Unix machines.
What&amp;rsquo;s a cron?
 Cron is nothing but an demon job running in the background without any user intervention. It gets executed automatically based on the predefined time interval.
 Generally cron jobs are used to perform some maintenance activities in the server. For example, if you run a very popular blog, you can use the cron job to send out a weekly mail to all the users about the new blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solution for Disk Drive Full error with USB Pen Drives</title>
      <link>http://purusothaman.me/solution-for-disk-drive-full-error-with-usb-pen-drives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2013 22:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://purusothaman.me/solution-for-disk-drive-full-error-with-usb-pen-drives/</guid>
      <description>When you copy large files (greater than 3 GB) to your USB pen drive, it&amp;rsquo;s almost sure that you will get an error alerting that &amp;ldquo;Disk drive is full&amp;rdquo;. I am sure you will be surprised on seeing this error as your USB pen drive will have more than 10 GB available. I swear, I did got surprised. I confirmed that my USB drive has enough space.
I spend some time on finding out why this happens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monsta FTP - FileZilla like FTP software for browsers</title>
      <link>http://purusothaman.me/monsta-ftp---filezilla-like-ftp-software-for-browsers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 18:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://purusothaman.me/monsta-ftp---filezilla-like-ftp-software-for-browsers/</guid>
      <description>You would have came across a FTP application like FileZilla or WinSCP which you have used to access a FTP server. These are Windows based and you need to install them on your desktop if you want to use them.
As a developer I commonly come across some situations where I need to access a FTP server but not in the position to use the FileZilla or install it. And again I was today in that situation and did a small research to find an alternative approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paris Desktop Wallpaper (HD)</title>
      <link>http://purusothaman.me/paris-desktop-wallpaper-hd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 10:12:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://purusothaman.me/paris-desktop-wallpaper-hd/</guid>
      <description>Download 7 high quality wallpapers for your computer. The image might load little slow as the size of each image is 3MB. You can save those images for your local copy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>