<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ispf on Purusothaman Ramanujam</title>
    <link>http://purusothaman.me/categories/ispf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ispf on Purusothaman Ramanujam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 08:59:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://purusothaman.me/categories/ispf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovering Deleted Flat Files in Mainframe</title>
      <link>http://purusothaman.me/recovering-deleted-flat-files-in-mainframe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 08:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://purusothaman.me/recovering-deleted-flat-files-in-mainframe/</guid>
      <description>Flat files can be recovered by following the below mentioned steps.
 Start 6 HLIST BCDS DSN(&amp;lsquo;filename&amp;rsquo;) Wait for the system notification Type the command HRECOVER &amp;lsquo;filename&amp;rsquo; and wait for system notification  Different variations of HRECOVER are given below.
 HRECOVER &amp;lsquo;filename&amp;rsquo; : recovers with same name. HRECOVER &amp;lsquo;old filename&amp;rsquo; NEW (&amp;lsquo;new filename&amp;rsquo;) : recovers and assigns new name. HRECOVER &amp;lsquo;file name&amp;rsquo; REPLACE : recovers replacing a file with same name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUTOTYPE Suggestion</title>
      <link>http://purusothaman.me/autotype-suggestion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 08:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://purusothaman.me/autotype-suggestion/</guid>
      <description>How wonderful it feels when Internet explorer suggests names for URLs when we start typing the first few letters!
Our mainframe also has the ability to do pretty much the same. Using KEYS command on the command line, assign a free PF key with the value AUTOTYPE. We are all set.

Now use 3.4 to go to the Data Set list utility and then type the first few qualifier of the required data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISPF Special Searching</title>
      <link>http://purusothaman.me/ispf-special-searching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://purusothaman.me/ispf-special-searching/</guid>
      <description>A picture string in a FIND, CHANGE, or EXCLUDE command allows you to search for a particular kind of character without regard for the specific character involved.
You can use special characters within the picture string to represent the kind of character to be found, as follows:
They can be used in REXX ISREDIT macros too.
   String Meaning     P&amp;rsquo;=&amp;rsquo; Any character   P&amp;rsquo;&amp;not;&amp;lsquo; Any character that is not a blank   P&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appending to ISPF Clipboard</title>
      <link>http://purusothaman.me/appending-to-ispf-clipboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 21:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://purusothaman.me/appending-to-ispf-clipboard/</guid>
      <description>Scenario: I have a dataset with 10,000 lines. I want to cut the first 10 lines and last 10 lines and paste into another dataset. When I cut the first 10 lines and then again the last 10 lines, only the last 10 lines are pasted into the new dataset.

Is there anyway out (other than doing a 2 cut &amp;amp; paste)?

Yes, here it is.
 First cut 10 lines, then issue CUT APPEND.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viewing Mainframe ISPF Clipboard</title>
      <link>http://purusothaman.me/viewing-mainframe-ispf-clipboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 20:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://purusothaman.me/viewing-mainframe-ispf-clipboard/</guid>
      <description>When I issue CUT , I know that the CUT content are placed in a clipboard. And when I issue PASTE, the clipboard content are pasted.
But is it possible for me to view and edit the clipboard?
One can view the clipboard after any valid CUT command was issued.
To view the clipboard, issue :
CUT DISPLAY  
Clipboard manager will pop up and gives us options to edit or browse the content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repeating the ISPF command without typing again</title>
      <link>http://purusothaman.me/repeating-the-ispf-command-without-typing-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 20:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://purusothaman.me/repeating-the-ispf-command-without-typing-again/</guid>
      <description>Any command entered in the ISPF COMMAND LINE disappears after the successful execution of its intended function. If you want to repeat the same command , you got to re-type it or use some PF key to retrieve the last command entered.
But here is a cool method the make the command entered not to disappear and stay on the screen.
Precede commands with &amp;ldquo;&amp;amp;&amp;ldquo;.
For Example:
 &amp;amp;C &amp;lsquo;110-PARA&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;220-PARA&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recently accessed Datasets in Mainframe</title>
      <link>http://purusothaman.me/recently-accessed-datasets-in-mainframe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 18:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://purusothaman.me/recently-accessed-datasets-in-mainframe/</guid>
      <description>Here is the way to find the last 10 datasets that you have accessed.
 GO TO ISPF 3.4 option. On the top, there is a MENUBAR. Select REFLIST Select Option 1 in it.  Using this option you can find out the last 30 datasets that you have accessed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>